<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[What's Shaking, NZ?]]></title>
  <link href="http://adamsp.github.com/wsnz-website/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://adamsp.github.com/wsnz-website/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-14T17:04:27+13:00</updated>
  <id>http://adamsp.github.com/wsnz-website/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Adam Speakman]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows Phone 7 update 1.3]]></title>
    <link href="http://adamsp.github.com/wsnz-website/blog/2012/12/14/windows-phone-7-update-1-dot-3/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-14T16:25:00+13:00</updated>
    <id>http://adamsp.github.com/wsnz-website/blog/2012/12/14/windows-phone-7-update-1-dot-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The latest version of What&#8217;s Shaking, NZ? for Windows Phone was <a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-nz/store/app/what-shaking-nz/8c5077db-6a9a-4c29-b095-42fea91874d9">published today</a>. This version has a few requested features, as well as a bit of additional information to keep you better informed about the earthquakes around New Zealand. Read on to find out more.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><a href="../../../../../windows-phone/screens/ss_01.png"><img class="left" src="../../../../../windows-phone/screens/ss_01.png" width="168" height="280" title="New quake location information" ></a></p>

<p>The list view has a useful new feature - it tells you where the quake was! This appears as text with a direction and a distance from a New Zealand town or city - for example &#8220;5km south of Christchurch.&#8221; This allows you to quickly glance through the listed quakes and then drill in on ones that are close to places of interest to you, and to easier see patterns in recent quakes.</p>

<p>On the quake detail page we now show the quakes &#8220;status&#8221; - primarily this will be either &#8216;automatic&#8217; or &#8216;reviewed&#8217;. You can tap on these words to get a pop-up describing what they mean, but basically &#8216;automatic&#8217; is a quake reported by the Geonet monitoring equipment, and &#8216;reviewed&#8217; means a Geonet technician has checked the quake, to make sure the equipment has provided an accurate report. Previously you had no way of knowing whether a quake was accurate or not - the initial automatic reports (within the first few minutes of a quake occurring) can be especially inaccurate.</p>

<p>We&#8217;ve also added the ability to view <em>all</em> recent earthquakes from around New Zealand. Previously, we were only showing you those which were likely to have been felt. You can toggle this on/off on the Settings page - it&#8217;s off by default. There are a <strong>lot</strong> of earthquakes that are never felt by people, so this is most likely not something you want turned on all the time.</p>

<p>These are the most noticeable changes. There have been a few changes behind the scenes, bug fixes and so-on, which you can <a href="https://github.com/adamsp/wsnz-windowsphone/commits/windows-phone-7.1">view on Github</a>.</p>

<p>Enjoy the latest update, and keep an eye out for a Windows Phone 8 version coming soon!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android version now available!]]></title>
    <link href="http://adamsp.github.com/wsnz-website/blog/2012/10/06/android-version-now-available/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-06T14:29:00+13:00</updated>
    <id>http://adamsp.github.com/wsnz-website/blog/2012/10/06/android-version-now-available</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today the Android version of What&#8217;s Shaking, NZ? was released on the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=speakman.whatsshakingnz">Google Play Store</a>.</p>

<p>Features include automatic alerts for new quakes, map and list view of recent quakes, full customisation and quake detail views. The app is completely free and open source, hosted on <a href="https://github.com/adamsp/wsnz-android">Github</a>.</p>

<p>You can read more about it on the <a href="android/">Android</a> page.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome!]]></title>
    <link href="http://adamsp.github.com/wsnz-website/blog/2012/08/22/welcome/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-22T19:51:00+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://adamsp.github.com/wsnz-website/blog/2012/08/22/welcome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the home of What&#8217;s Shaking, NZ? - a quake monitoring app designed for New Zealand. It is currently available on the <a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-NZ/apps/8c5077db-6a9a-4c29-b095-42fea91874d9">Windows Phone Marketplace</a> with an Android version on the way.</p>

<p>Features include:</p>

<ul>
<li>Uses the latest <a href="http://beta.geonet.org.nz/quakes/felt">Geonet Rapid</a> data feed for up-to-the-minute quake information.</li>
<li>Both list and a map overviews of the latest quakes.</li>
<li>Allows you to select how many quakes you&#8217;d like to see presented at once.</li>
<li>And more!</li>
</ul>


<p>For more detail (and screenshots!), see the <a href="http://adamsp.github.com/wsnz-website/windows-phone">Windows Phone</a> page.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
